Himank Jha

Interaction/Visual Designer

Seasoned Interaction/Visual Designer with 9+ years of experience to enhance customer satisfaction by improving the usability and accessibility associated with a product in a way that is attractive and convenient for users. Focused on designing and developing user-centered products from initial concept to final, polished deliverable.

Work Experience

Metacube Software / Sr. Interaction Designer

MAY 2017 - PRESENT, JAIPUR

- Work extensively on Salesforce platform to design and integrate designs patterns/layouts strictly as per SLDS(Salesforce lightning design system) standards.
- Driving the development and communication of clear design guidelines, patterns, libraries and assets.
- Supervise the assessment of all UI/UX materials in order to ensure quality and accuracy of the design
- Identify and resolve flaws, conduct user research and analysis, and propose new ideas to improve the user experience of the product/application.
- Presenting UX design concepts to the project stakeholders to review and feedback.
- Presenting and preparing lo-fi mockups to internal teams and key stakeholders.
- Creating wireframes, site maps, flow diagrams and hi-fi interactive prototypes.

Nine Hertz Pvt. Ltd. / Visual Designer & UX Engineer

MARCH 2015 - MAY 2017, JAIPUR

- Facilitated design strategy workshops and designed web and mobile products for multiple clients.
- Synthesized learnings and communicated ideas to product manager to contribute to the product strategy.
- Delegate tasks to the multiple members of the design team and provide counsel on all aspects of the project.

smartData Enterprises / Associate Designer

JULY 2012 - FEBRUARY 2015, CHANDIGARH

- Collaborated with development teams and managed a wide variety of cross-media projects involving branding, illustrations and UI designs.
- Extensive training to design apps and web mockups and respective HTML framework integration.
- Designed interactive user interfaces for mobile applications on multiple platforms like IOS, Android and hybrid applications.

☑ dv.himank@gmail.com

\(+91-9929915037

in linkedin.com/himank-jha

Skills

UX: Wireframes and Mockups • Strategy & Vision Presentations with FIGMA • User flows • Concept Sketches • Interaction design • Visual design • Style guides and pattern library

UI: HTML/CSS • JS Frameworks • Responsive Design • Browser Developer Tools • GitHub Bootstrap

Soft Skills: Collaboration • Communication Creative Thinking • Detail Oriented • Problem Solving • Critical Thinking • Active Listening • Interpersonal Skills

Certifications

Google UX Design Professional Certificate



Language

A1 level certified in Spanish Language

Certificate issued by <u>Instituto Cervantes</u>, a public institution founded by the Government of Spain.

Portfolio

Dribbble Handle: <u>creative himank</u> **Website Link:** <u>himank.github.io</u>

Education

ICFAI Institute / B.Tech

AUG 2008 - JULY 2012, DEHRADUN